

# **Maheswar Reddy B**

Associate - Projects, Cognizant, Bangalore

Mail : maheswarreddy954@gmail.com

Mobile : +91- 93478 06781

## **Technical Skills**

Operating Systems : LINUX and WINDOWS 9x/2000.

Languages : JAVA, Web Services.

Framework : Hybris, Spring.

Java Technologies : SERVLETS, JDBC and JSP.

Designing : CSS, AJAX, jQuery, JavaScript, HTML.

IDEs : My Eclipse6.0, Net Beans.

Application Server : JBOSSAS 7.1/6.0/4.0, GlassFish3.

Web Server : Tomcat 7.

Configuration Tools : SVN, Log4j, Ant, Maven.

Database : ORACLE 9i/11g, MySQL

# **Experience Summary**

Mr. Maheswar Reddy is Associate with **4.5 Years of IT Experience in developing e-commerce and end-to-end Enterprise applications**. Having 3.5 years of Experience in E-commerce applications development using HYBRIS Frameworks. Good exposure on e-commerce B2C (Business to Consumer) and B2B (Business to Business) modules using Sap Hybris Multichannel suite. Good amount of experience in Full Software Development Life Cycle including Requirement gathering, Analysis, Design, Development, Deployment and Maintenance of web applications.

# **Professional Experience**

Cognizant Technology Solutions India Pvt. Ltd.

Associate - Projects Aug 2019 to Present

Title: AB Electrolux D2C Transformer Wave

Client: Electrolux

**Role Definition:** SAP Hybris developer **Environment:** SAP Hybris 1905, SAP ECC

Duration: Aug 2019 to present

# **Project Description:**

Electrolux is Swedish multinational home appliance manufacturer, headquartered in Stockholm. Electrolux is running their business online on legacy system but with the dynamically changing technology and growth of their business they planned to develop multi country portal. The implementation is for two brands rollout (Electrolux and AEG) in two different countries (Italy – Electrolux and Germany - AEG). The commerce capabilities are exposed via OCC and getting integrated till basket page on the brand sites (via REST APIs). From checkout page onwards, the page is rendered on CCv2.



#### Responsibilities:

- Development based on given requirements and use cases.
- Worked on Services details on PDP, Checkout and Order confirmation Page.
- Worked on Promotions in Checkout and Order confirmation Page
- Worked on Order confirmation Page.

# **Previous Experience**

IBM Private Ltd.
Software Engineer

June 2015 to Aug 2019

Title: ABC B2B

Client: AmerisourceBergen

**Role Definition:** SAP Hybris developer **Environment:** SAP Hybris 5.7, SAP ECC

Duration: Jan 2018 to present

#### **Project Description:**

AmerisourceBergen Corporation is an American drug wholesale company that was formed by the merger of Bergen Brunswig and AmerisourceBergen in 2001. They provide drug distribution and related services designed to reduce costs and improve patient outcomes, distribute a line of brand name and generic pharmaceuticals.

This is B2B project built on Sap Hybris. This is one of the User Interface for order capturing and handling order returns and claims. Using different Web services/RFC calls for communicating with the Sap ECC system.

#### Responsibilities:

- Development based on given requirements and use cases.
- Provide support to fixing issues and defects for the stability of the application.
- SAP Order Export Integration as per the requirements.
- Order Process Handling and notifications handling.
- Worked on orders, invoices and self-services.

Title: Maplin

**Client:** Maplin Electronics

Role Definition: SAP Hybris developer

Environment: SAP Hybris 5.7, SAP ECC, Power BI

Duration: April 2016 to Dec 2017

#### **Project Description:**

Maplin Electronics is a electronic goods' retailer in UK and Ireland. Medtronic Spine application is a B2C application built on SAP Hybris platform. It is a migration project from 5.0 to 5.7.

#### Responsibilities:

- Worked on check out process customization like home delivery, click and collect flow and combinational flow.
- Worked on Payment Integration with PayPal, Sage-Pay as payment provider.
- Worked on Gift card process related issues.
- Worked on address tab related issues in payment process.
- Worked on payments and search defects.
- Created new Cronjobs for user notifications.
- Provide support to fixing issues and defects for the stability of the application.



Title: Late Night Cab Deployment

Client: IBM Pvt Ltd

Role Definition: Java Developer

**Environment:** Spring 2.5, JSP, Hibernate and Oracle

Duration: June 2015 to Feb 2016

#### **Project Description:**

Late night cab facility is mainly developed to provide efficient and safety transport management system for IBM employees during night shifts by providing an easy way of registration process where user should register his details by providing employee id, employee name and the location. The request goes to administrator, then admin approves the employee request for transportation and process the request by generating a confirmation mail to the employee and avail the safe and secure transport facility. Employee can opt for Late night cab between 10pm to 6am. He should raise the cab request minimum 2 hours before of his travel and if the user needs to cancel the cab, he needs to cancel it minimum 1 hour before of this travel.

#### Responsibilities:

- Developed user interface using HTML and JSPs.
- Involved in developing the code.
- Actively participated in code review issues fixing.
- Involved in server-side business validations by using Struts frame work.
- Involved in preparing the Unit Test Cases

## **Education**

Institution

Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University, Anantapur, India

Bachelor of Technology – 2014

#### **Declaration:**

I hereby declare that above mentioned information is true to the best of my knowledge. If given an opportunity, I will serve to the best of my abilities for your esteemed organization.

Place: Bangalore (Maheswar Reddy B)

Date: